Moustakis Family Papers MS082
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Photographs and films, 1905 -- 2006; 1910 -- 1998; MS082.002; 3.4 Linear Feet
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - Soldiers killed and people massacred, MS082.002.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00036 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, MS082.002.004.00037 (Box 4)
  - Princess Nicholas with doctors and nurses, MS082.002.004.00038 (Box 4)
  - Queen Sophia and Princess Helen, MS082.002.004.00039 (Box 4)
  - King Constantine and Queen Sophia, MS082.002.004.00040 (Box 4)
  - Royal family seated at the dinner table, MS082.002.004.00041 (Box 4)
  - Photograph of knighthood banquet for Constantine C. Moustakis, 1924; MS082.002.006.001 (Box Shared 46)
    Photograph of the banquet at the Copley Plaza Hotel, Boston, Mass., April 30, 1924, in honor of Constantine C. Moustakis on the decoration of his decoration by the Greek government with the gold cross of Chevalier of the Order of King George the First; presented by His Excellency, Michael Tsamados, Greek Ambassador in Washington.
  - "Trotsky" two-hour IMA Telefilm, 1988; MS082.002.007.00008 (Box MS082 Shared 2)
    Needs to be digitally reformatted. Maxell epitaxial videocassette T-120 EX. French language film by Alain Dugrand and Patrick Le Gall. - Paris: IMA Productions, 1988. Videocassette release of a film originally produced as a TV programme of FR3 (France) in 1988 with French historian Pierre Broué as scientific counselor. This is a documentary portrait of Trotsky by photos, filmclips and interviews with several contemporaries and historians.
    videocassette
  - Trotsky film, 1990; MS082.002.007.00009 (Box MS082 Shared 2)
    Needs to be digitally reformatted. TDK SuperStrong VHS. Label of film is in Japanese. Original label reads NHK re: Trotsky.
  - Trotsky's Home Movies, 1990; MS082.002.007.00010 (Box MS082 Shared 2)
    Needs to be digitally reformatted. Sony HG-ES T-120 Dynamicron. Original label reads: "Trotsky Home Movie" about 60 minutes. British television channel 4 broadcast 8/20/1990. Copy June 1, 1991. Label on VHS reads: "Trotsky Home Movies" British channel 4 broadcast Aug 20, 1990 on 50th anniv. of Trotsky's assassination.
- Published material, 1909 -- 2003; 1910 -- 1998; MS082.003; 1.7 Linear Feet
  This series contains newspaper clippings arranged by language (English and Greek) photocopied onto acid-free paper, an original Greek newspaper, Nov.-Dec. 1924 containing article on Moustakis knighthood; periodical clippings arranged by language (English and Greek) photocopied onto acid-free paper, and an original periodical, ca. 1914, containing an article about the Moustakis family; and published material Christy Moustakis collected regarding Leon Trotsky and Marxism, including a book, Trotsky in Mexico.
  - Newspaper articles in English, 1909 -- 1925; MS082.003.002.00042 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - Newspaper articles in Greek, 1909 -- 1925; MS082.003.002.00043 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - Article on Constantine C. Moustakis (Eastern and Western Review), 1914; MS082.003.002.00044 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
    Article includes photographs of many family members.
  - Periodical articles in English, MS082.003.002.00045 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - Periodical articles in Greek, MS082.003.002.00046 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - Published material and articles on Trotsky and Marxism collected by Christy C. Moustakis, MS082.003.002.00047 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - Published material and articles on Trotsky and Marxism collected by Christy C. Moustakis, MS082.003.002.00048 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
  - An Ardent Republican, a Defender of Greece: Article and correspondence, 2003; MS082.003.002.00051 (Box MS082 Shared 1)
    Folder contains article by Stavros T. Stavridis about Constantine Moustakis, as well as a letter to the editor and a letter to the author from George Marcopoulos.
  - Constantine Moustakis - political clippings, 1919 -- 1924; MS082.003.007.00006 (Box MS082 Shared 2)
  - Trotsky in Mexico, 1937-1940, 1992; MS082.003.007.00007 (Box MS082 Shared 2)
    Book from Christy Moustakis' library by Alain Dugrand. Information about Alex Buchman photographs glued on the first page.